JONATHAN SOBIER

32782 Meadowpark Ln. Trabuco Canyon, CA 92679

C: 949-690-1553 E-mail: jonsobier@outlook.com Website: http://www.jonsobier.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A hard-working and experienced individual seeking employment with an employer who can benefit from the excellent customer service skills acquired during 20+ years of retail experience as well as skills and expertise learned from various Web Development courses completed while earning a Bachelor's Degree in Web Development.

SKILLS

- Excellent customer service skills
- · Hourly shift management
- POS systems
- Merchandising and store displays
- Bank deposit procedures
- · Goal-oriented
- Detail-oriented
- Staff training and development
- Opening and closing procedures

- Proficient in Microsoft Office programs.
- Strongest in MS Excel, MS Word, and MS PowerPoint.
- Tech savvy and a quick learner in all areas.
- Genuinely loves a busy environment where new things are learned all the time.
- Proficiency in the following website coding languages: HTML5 and CSS, PHP, Python, JavaScript and JQuery ,Java SE and EE, Ruby on Rails.

- 71 wpm with 99% accuracy on 1minute typing test
- 72 wpm with 98% accuracy on 3minute typing test
- 65 wpm with 97% accuracy on 5minute typing test
- 11,885 KPH with 99.4% accuracy on 10-key typing test.
- Proficient with Adobe Software.

WORK HISTORY

Sales Associate

Pet Supply OC - Rancho Santa Margarita, CA

August 2017 to Present Day

- Count cash drawers both before opening store and after closing.
- Stock shelves from daily deliveries or from merchandise that has been placed in backstock from earlier shipments.
- Help customers and advise them on the best food and/or diet for their pets.
- Attend training meetings with food company representatives and use new knowledge and methods of selling with customers.
- Clean and maintain a neat, organized, and stocked sales floor.
- Check food weekly and for any that may be on the shelf after the expiration date printed on the bag.

Store Manager

July 2010 to March 2016

Spencer Gifts – West Covina and Westminster, CA

- Promoted from Assistant Manager to Store Manager within an 18-month period.
- Interviewed job candidates and made staffing decisions.
- Counted cash drawers and made bank deposits.
- Managed staff of 4-7 sales associates, 1-2 team leaders and 1 assistant manager.
- Assigned employees to specific duties to best meet the needs of the store.
- Examined merchandise to verify that it was correctly priced and displayed.
- Scheduled and led monthly store meetings for all employees.
- Increased profits through effective sales training and troubleshooting profit loss areas.
- Reported to the District Manager regarding all store and staff issues.
- Trained and developed new associates on POS system and key sales tactics.
- Increased sales volume by 143% in less than 2 full years.
- Conducted store inventory once per year.
- Lowered store Shrink from a 2.20% in October 2012 down to a 0.86% in July 2014.

Assistant Store Manager

Pier 1 Imports – Mission Viejo, CA

- · Interviewed job candidates and made staffing decisions, teaming up with the store manager when deciding who to hire.
- Counted cash drawers and made bank deposits.
- Managed staff of 10-20 sales associates and 2-3 team leaders.
- Assigned employees to specific duties to best meet the needs of the store.
- Examined merchandise to verify that it was correctly priced and displayed.
- Increased profits through effective sales training and troubleshooting profit loss areas.
- Reported to the Store Manager regarding all store and staff issues.
- Trained and developed new associates on POS system and key sales tactics.
- Conducted store inventory once per year.

Assistant Store Manager

August 2000 to March 2004

Waldenbooks – Mission Viejo and Brea, CA

- Promoted from sales associate to a key-holder in just 3-months and then promoted to Assistant manager within the next 6 months.
- Interviewed job candidates and made staffing decisions, teaming up with the store manager when deciding who to hire.
- Counted cash drawers and made bank deposits.
- Assigned employees to specific duties to best meet the needs of the store.
- Examined merchandise to verify that it was correctly priced and displayed.
- Reported to the Store Manager regarding all store and staff issues.
- Trained and developed new associates on POS system and key sales tactics.
- · Conducted store inventory once per year.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Applied Sciences: Web Development **Baker College Online** – Flint, MI and Online

Currently Enrolled Completion in Spring 2019

- Coursework in all areas of Web development and Web design as well as a focus on required general education subjects.
- Emphasis in Web development using Adobe Dreamweaver and other Adobe Creative Suite programs.
- Cumulative GPA of 3.71 from 98 completed course credits.
- Listed on the Dean's list and/or the President's list at Baker College during most of semesters completed since enrolling in 2016.
- Received a nomination for membership into the Baker College Online chapter of The National Society of Collegiate Scholars.

REFERENCES

References available upon request.